yadvashem.org 2010-11-22

# Privacy Policy - Yad Vashem

### Privacy Policy

#### Introduction

Thank you for visiting the Yad Vashem – the Holocaust Heroes’ and Martyrs’ Remembrance Authority (“Yad Vashem”) website and reviewing our privacy policy.

This is our policy: We will collect no personal information about you when you visit our website unless you choose to provide that information to us.

Here is how we handle information about your visit to our website:

#### Information Collected and Stored Automatically

  1. The IP Address from which you access our website
  2. The name of the domain from which you access the internet
  3. The type of browser and operating system used to access our website
  4. The date and time you access our website
  5. The pages, files, documents and links that you visit
  6. The internet address of the website from which you linked to this website

#### Cookies

In addition to information collected automatically, we may also collect cookies, which are small pieces of information sent to your browser by a website that you visit. Cookies are used to track usage patterns, traffic trends and customer behavior, as well as to record other information from the Website. When you register on the Website, cookies also allow us to save information so that you will not have to re-enter it the next time you visit. Many content adjustments and customer service improvements are made based on the data derived from cookies. Information that we collect from cookies will not be used to create profiles of users and only will be used in aggregate form.

You may set your browser to refuse cookies from any website that you visit. If you so choose, you may still gain access to most of Yad Vashem’s Website, but you may not be able to conduct certain types of transactions (such as shopping) or take advantage of some of the interactive elements offered.

#### Sending Us Personal Information

Yad Vashem’s Website will only collect personal information which you knowingly and voluntarily provide by, for example, sending emails, submitting Pages of Testimony, registering for on-line courses, events, or other programs, responding to surveys or ordering merchandise. If you provide us with personal information, we will normally respond to your inquiry, request or order. We may also contact you to provide information about Yad Vashem activities, programs, membership and development opportunities, products and special events that may interest you. We will not knowingly provide access to your personal information outside Yad Vashem unless you affirmatively authorize us to do so by opting-in.

When we send you such information by email, you will have an opportunity to decline further communication. Please use the contact specified in the email so that we can remove you from the list that contains your name. If you are uncertain about whom to contact, you may contact our webmaster at [ webmaster@yadvashem.org.il](mailto:webmaster@yadvashem.org.il).

####  Children and Privacy

Yad Vashem is concerned about protecting children’s privacy. We do not collect age-related information from children through our site. We further advise that children under the age of 13 get permission from their parent/guardian before sending any information to the Yad Vashem website.

#### Security

Yad Vashem’s online stores are hosted on the The Government Mall - which is a new initiative of the Department of Information Systems of the Accountant General in the Ministry of Finance of the State of Israel.

The Government Mall's staff put many resources into creating a secured system which will maintain data integrity, based on the most advanced tools in the field. Sophisticated secured servers protect the site's systems, the billing process and the supply operation.

The site's system is blocked and secured, while communicating with customers and while communicating with the system's servers. In every purchase, the customer is requested to enter a name and a password  which was set in advance. Entering the password enables the privacy needed and the control of each customer over the purchase.

All the client's details, including the current billing, is kept on the system in a secured server which is not accessible, but to a limited number of authorized users. The Government Mall assures that there will be no use of the information which is submitted to the site in a way that contradicts commercial regulations and that sensitive information will not be transferred to third parties.

The Government Mall’s Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) software is the industry standard and among the best software available today for secure online commerce transactions. It encrypts all of your personal information, including credit card number, name, and address, so that it cannot be read as the information travels over the Internet.

The credit card information is not kept in the system's database, and is used for the purpose of the current bill alone. Therefore, even an actual burglary to the system's servers will not reveal the customer's information.

As another precaution, a thorough verification of the client's credit card information is conducted with the credit card company on every purchase, to eliminate any disorder or misuse of the credit card.

For more information, [click here](http://secure.yadvashem.org/store/).

####  Linking

Within Yad Vashem’s Website, there are links to non-Yad Vashem websites. When you link to third party websites, you leave our Website and no longer will be subject to our privacy policy. Yad Vashem is not responsible for the privacy practices nor the content of non-Yad Vashem websites, and such link is not intended to be an endorsement of the non-Yad Vashem website or its content. 

**Please Note: Our Privacy Policy may change from time to time. We therefore recommend that you review this Privacy Policy regularly to ensure that you are familiar with our privacy practices.   ** ** **

**In any event, Yad Vashem shall not bear any liability of any kind, explicit or implicit, if it shall not maintain the privacy of the user as detailed hereinabove, whether in whole or in part, for any reason whatsoever.**
